UNIVERISTY HISTORICAL REFERENCE COLLECTION (UA950.008) 1871-1995
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
Univeristy Historical Reference Collection1871-1995
nam_ua950.008
This collection is made up of reference material related to the history of the University at Albany and its earlier iterations.
State University of New York at Albany
2.31
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, University at Albany, SUNY
Administrative History
There have been many different histories of the New York State Normal School, The New York State Normal College, The New York State College for Teachers, and the State University of New York at Albany. As early as 1884 there was a history of the New York State Normal School published. Since then there has been expanions to that hsitory, as well as original works focusing on the more recent iterations of the School.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of various publications focusing on the history of the New York Satte Normal School, New York State Normal College, New York State College for Teachers, and the State University of New York at Albany. These histories cover a range of dates related to the institutions. It includes publications from the 1880's up to the book "Tradition of Excellence: 1844 to 1994" by Kandell A. Birr.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is arranged in chronological order.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Subject and Genre Headings
Reference Books; Education--History; Albany, New York
Container List
- Catalogue of the Graduates of the Sate Normal School, 1871 (Volume 1)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1884 (Volume 2)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1884 (Volume 3)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1884 (Volume 4)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1884 (Volume 5)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1888 (Volume 6)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1888 (Volume 7)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1888 (Volume 8)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal School at Albany, 1894 (Volume 9)
- A Historical Sketch of the State Normal College at Albany, 1918 (Volume 10)
- New York State College for Teachers: Master's Theses Directory 1914-1931 (Volume 11)
- New York State College for Teachers: Master's Theses Directory 1933-1937, 1938 (Volume 12)
- College of the Empire State: A Centennial History, 1944 (Volume 13)
- A Liberal arts in the Curricula for the Preparation of Teachers, 1967 (Volume 14)
- Short History of the Graduate School of Public Affairs, 1971 (Volume 15)
- Establishment of the School of criminal Justice, 1976 (Volume 16)
- Center and Institutes: A Directory, 1982 (Volume 17)
- State University of New York at Albany: 1844-1984 A Short History (Volume 18)
- Center and Institutes: A Directory, 1987 (Volume 19)
- Center and Institutes: A Directory, 1987 (Volume 20)
- A Draft History of the State University of New York, 1988 (Volume 21)
- Center and Institutes: A Directory, 1990 (Volume 22)
- History of the University at Albany, 1990 (Volume 23)
- A Tradition of Excellence: a Sesquicentennial Commemoration, 1994 (Volume 24)
- Tradition of Excellence, Final Draft, ca. 1994 (Volume 25)
- Tradition of Excellence, Early, longer drafts, ca. 1994 (Volume 26)
- Tradition of Excellence, 1994 (Volume 27)
- Tradition of Excellence Photographs: Chapters 1-3, 1994 (Volume 28)
- Tradition of Excellence Photographs: Chapters 4-5, 1994 (Volume 29)
- Tradition of Excellence Photographs: Chapters 6-8, 1994 (Volume 30)
- An Investigation into the Benefits of Having an Africana Studies Master's Degree, 1995 (Volume 31)